<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- App name -->
    <string name="app_name">Rolling Text</string>

    <!-- UI Labels -->
    <string name="title_text">Rolling Text</string>
    <string name="hint_text">Start typing…</string>
    <string name="default_counter">0 / 128</string>
    <string name="limit_label">(oldest text removed when limit reached)</string>
    <string name="char_counter_format">%1$d / %2$d</string>

    <!-- Button labels -->
    <string name="button_char_limit">Char Limit</string>
    <string name="button_theme">Theme</string>
    <string name="button_font">Font</string>

    <!-- Content descriptions for accessibility -->
    <string name="desc_change_limit">Change character limit</string>
    <string name="desc_choose_font">Choose font</string>
    <string name="desc_change_theme">Change theme. Current theme is %s mode</string>
    <string name="desc_change_font_size">Change font size</string>

    <!-- Dialog titles -->
    <string name="dialog_title_limit">Set Character Limit</string>
    <string name="dialog_title_warning">Warning</string>
    <string name="dialog_title_theme">Select Theme</string>
    <string name="dialog_title_font">Select Font</string>
    <string name="dialog_title_font_size">Set Font Size</string>
    <string name="dialog_title_error">Invalid Input</string>

    <!-- Dialog messages -->
    <string name="dialog_loading_fonts">Loading fonts…</string>

    <!-- Plurals for truncation warning -->
    <plurals name="dialog_warning_truncate_plurals">
        <item quantity="one">This will remove %d character from the beginning of your text. Continue?</item>
        <item quantity="other">This will remove %d characters from the beginning of your text. Continue?</item>
    </plurals>

    <!-- Button labels for dialogs -->
    <string name="button_ok">OK</string>
    <string name="button_yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="button_no">No</string>
    <string name="button_cancel">Cancel</string>

    <!-- Theme names -->
    <string name="theme_light">Light</string>
    <string name="theme_dark">Dark</string>
    <string name="theme_sepia">Sepia</string>

    <!-- Font names -->
    <string name="font_system_default">System Default</string>

    <!-- Toast messages -->
    <string name="toast_no_fonts">No custom fonts found on device</string>
    <string name="toast_error_fonts">Error loading fonts</string>
    <string name="toast_font_error">Could not load font. Using default.</string>
    <string name="toast_font_too_large">Font file is too large. Using default.</string>

    <!-- Error messages -->
    <string name="error_invalid_number">Please enter a valid number</string>
    <string name="error_number_range">Please enter a number between 1 and 1,000,000</string>

    <!-- Accessibility announcements -->
    <string name="announce_theme_changed">Theme changed to %s mode</string>

    <!-- About screen -->
    <string name="button_about">About</string>
    <string name="desc_about">About Rolling Text</string>
    <string name="button_back">Back</string>
    <string name="about_title">About Rolling Text</string>
    <string name="about_intro">We all carry thoughts we wish we didn\'t. The worries that keep us up at night. The harsh things we say to ourselves. The moments we replay over and over even though we can\'t change them. That\'s just part of being human, and it can be really heavy.</string>
    <string name="about_concept">Rolling Text is a simple place to set those thoughts down. As you type, your words quietly disappear. Nothing is saved. Nothing is stored. You don\'t have to organize your feelings or make them make sense. Just let them out, and let them go.</string>
    <string name="about_power">There\'s something powerful about putting a difficult thought into words and then watching it leave. You\'re not ignoring what you feel. You\'re giving yourself permission to feel it, express it, and release it.</string>
    <string name="about_science_intro">And it turns out, science agrees.</string>
    <string name="about_study1_title">Writing down your thoughts and letting them go actually works.</string>
    <string name="about_study1_body">Researchers found that when people wrote down negative thoughts and then discarded them, even digitally by dragging them to the recycle bin on a computer, those thoughts lost their grip. They had significantly less influence on emotions and self-perception afterward. It wasn\'t just the writing that helped. It was the act of letting go.</string>
    <string name="about_study1_citation">Briñol, Petty, Gascó &amp; Horcajo, 2012, Psychological Science</string>
    <string name="about_study2_title">Putting your feelings into words is a form of healing.</string>
    <string name="about_study2_body">Over four decades of research on expressive writing, pioneered by psychologist James Pennebaker, has shown that writing about what\'s bothering us, even for just a few minutes, can meaningfully improve both our emotional and physical well-being. You don\'t have to write well. You just have to write honestly.</string>
    <string name="about_study2_citation">Pennebaker, 2018, Perspectives on Psychological Science</string>
    <string name="about_study3_title">You are not your thoughts.</string>
    <string name="about_study3_body">In Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT), a practice called cognitive defusion helps people step back and see their thoughts for what they really are: passing mental events, not permanent truths. Research shows that this kind of distance reduces both the pain and the believability of harsh, self-critical thoughts more effectively than trying to distract yourself or push them away.</string>
    <string name="about_study3_citation">Masuda et al., 2004, Behavior Therapy; Larsson et al., 2016, Behavior Modification</string>
    <string name="about_study4_title">Letting go isn\'t weakness. It\'s a skill.</string>
    <string name="about_study4_body">A 2023 study from the University of Cambridge found that people who practiced actively releasing unwanted thoughts experienced less anxiety, less depression, and fewer intrusive negative emotions. This was true even for those living with clinical mental health conditions. Sometimes the bravest thing you can do is choose not to hold on.</string>
    <string name="about_study4_citation">Mamat et al., 2023, Science Advances</string>
    <string name="about_closing">Rolling Text isn\'t therapy, and it\'s not a replacement for professional support. If you\'re struggling, please reach out to someone who can help. But for the everyday weight of being human, for the thoughts that just need somewhere to go, this is a quiet place to let them pass through.</string>
</resources>
